Email: <u>brycetham@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>http://www.brycetham.com</u>

OVERVIEW

I am a graduate student pursuing a master's degree in computer science at Stanford University with depth in human-computer interaction. I have experience in several programming languages, most notably Python and Java, and also in web development and database design. In the past, I have been an intern at the UCI Office of Information Technology as well as a research assistant at the UCI Institute for Software Research. I am interested in software engineering, human-computer interaction, and data informatics.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Science, Class of 2019

Stanford University
Depth in Human-Computer Interaction
4.000 GPA, Honor Society Invitee

B.S. in Computer Science, Class of 2017

University of California, Irvine Dual Specialization in Information & Algorithms 3.993 GPA, Summa Cum Laude, Honors in ICS

SKILLS (by order of strength)

Programming:Database Design:Web Development:Python, JavaSQL/MySQL, InformaticaHTML/CSS, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

AR Applications Research Assistant | UCI Institute for Software Research

April 2016 – August 2017

- Worked with Dr. Walt Scacchi on an IoT-based augmented reality project for smart workers in advanced manufacturing.
- Researched training techniques and interactive game-based systems to illustrate conceptual augmented learning.
- Wrote design documents, attributed directed graph models, and problem specifications for the manufacturing simulation.
- Created a prototype illustrating the conceptual implications of augmented reality in the context of real manufacturing settings.

Data Warehouse Developer Intern | UCI Office of Information Technology

April 2015 - August 2017

- Compared and wrote reports for hundreds of tables during the company's database migration away from Talend.
- Developed dozens of Informatica ETL mappings and sessions as part of the legacy ODS conversion.
- Updated the Data Warehouse website with new content including resolving security issues caused by SQL injection.
- Upgraded the online query-by-example ad-hoc tool in the DWH BLISS Enhancement project with various functionality additions.

Technology Chair | Circle K International

April 2015 - March 2016

- Managed content and resources for members including general information, weekly updates, calendar events, and media.
- Developed new features and tools for the website such as a personal events portal and a smart announcements system.
- Managed a group of 4 students in organizing the club's first Technology Internship Program.
- Received the Distinguished Appointed Board Officer award for demonstrating excellent achievement in service.

Lab Tutor | Donald Bren School of ICS

September 2014 - March 2015

- Tutored over 50 students in various ICS courses including Programming with Software Libraries and Intermediate Programming.
- Wrote pedagogical materials as resources for future students and proctored/facilitated in-lab examinations.

PROJECTS (see website for full list)

goFIT (Programmer/Designer)

September 2017 – Present

goFIT is a mobile application to help you stay healthy, be social, and accomplish goals. Set personal health and fitness goals, log your progress, and challenge your friends to get in on the action.

Completed for: dt+UX; Programmed in: Swift

Bubble Buddy (Programmer/Designer)

April 2016

Bubble Buddy is a web-based virtual communication companion designed for young children with autism who struggle with communication, identifying emotions, and learning by interacting with them using typical everyday conversation.

Completed for: Autism App Jam 2016; Programmed in: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MEAN stack; Awards: Winner (2nd Place), Hype Award

Fabflix (Programmer)

January 2016 - March 2016

Fabflix is a web-based interface that allows customers to browse/search for movie information, add interesting movies to their shopping cart, and check out.

Completed for: Project in Databases and Web Applications; Programmed in: Java, HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap

UC Irvine Circle K Website (*Programmer/Administrator*)

April 2015 - March 2016

The UC Irvine Circle K Website utilizes key web development techniques and open-source software solutions to create a reliable and robust website as a resource hub for members and a means of organizing club secretarial information.

Completed for: Circle K International; Programmed in: HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap; Awards: Outstanding Club Website (1st Place)